This is my kitchen table and also my
filing system.
Over much of the past three decades,
I've been an investor the highest
calling of mankind I've often thought
was private equity.
And then I started interviewing.
While I watch your interviews, Coach, I
know how to do something.
I've learned in doing my interviews how
leaders make it to the top.
I asked him how much he wanted.
He said to 50.
I said, Fine.
I didn't negotiate with him.
I didn't know due diligence to have
something I'd like to sell and how they
stay there.
You don't feel inadequate now because
being only the second wealthiest man in
the world, is that right?
The world's best known banker is Jamie
Dimon, the long time CEO of JPMorgan.
I had a chance to meet with Jamie Dimon
recently to talk about what's going on
in the financial world.
He said he didn't want to be chairman of
the Federal Reserve Board, but maybe he
would take the call to be secretary of
the Treasury.
So recently you've been talking about
the importance of the United States and
our celebrate our 250th, but also
investing in things that are security
related.
What made you focus on that?
And you're now going to commit to build
a trillion a half dollars over next ten
years for this kind of investment?
Why did you decide to do that?
Yeah, So I've always been a patriot.
And like, you know, you talk here about
growth.
You know, growing the economy and the
grievances of America, which has a lot
of legitimate we got to deal with and
get policy right.
But one of them was this notion that we
ended up being so reliant on other
people, some potential adversaries, for
things critical to the security of the
United States.
And it wasn't just us was your allies,
too.
So we did some real research, of course,
to industry groups.
You're talking about rare earths, which
you all know about active pharmaceutical
ingredients some of you may know about,
you know, obviously military production,
drones, air, cyber, satellite.
What are the things you need for
resiliency that we already did a lot of
it.
And we wanted to do more, realizing it
was an important thing to do.
How we got here.
I don't like to have spilled milk, but
we should never have been here.
So that's a three and a half dollars.
My guess is will be quite a bit more
than that by the time we're done.
We've had a deluge of interest in it.
Then we have we hired Todd Combs, who
was just a world class investor and a
world class person who's got his own
dealers coming in to invest, you know,
10 billion and probably more.
And we actually have partners in that in
helping companies with growth capital
that they need to grow to build a next
plant or something.
We did real research of supply chains.
It was a lot of companies that provide
what's important for basic, important
military equipment and they need help to
grow that they could be private
companies or bigger companies.
There's a venture capital component.
We're also under research.
So think around the shipbuilding
ecosystem and then and policy.
There are a lot of things that are wrong
or policy reasons are how we how we're
allowed to procure in the military,
things like permitting EPA laws.
You know, if you want to keep this
country safe and secure, we need to do
this work.
We need to do it now.
And right away, it also will be extended
to, you know, nations in Europe, you
know, Australia, Japan, South Korea.
And it's just important to our national
security.
You know, if you didn't if you didn't
get the wakeup call in February when,
you know, 300,000 Russian troops and
then Ukraine, you know, the was not
safe.
It was never say if we just got another
false sense of security, the biggest
safe thing to have is the strongest
military on the planet.
When the Great Recession happened.
Were you worried about the viability of
our financial system?
Your bank was in pretty good shape, but
we worried that more many investment
banks and commercial banks were to go
under at that point.
Well, a lot of them did.
You know, and yeah, a lot of companies
around the world, a lot of non-banks
around the world, went bankrupt.
You know, Jp morgan, we did a lot to
keep people afloat.
We took a lot of risk to do that.
We worked with governments around the
world.
It was it was terrifying and it was, you
know, 24, seven.
And, you know, people just try to do the
right thing and make sure, you know, we
can.
Do you think there's a chance of
something like that happening next
couple of years?
Do you think we're much better protected
from that kind of problem?
Well, there's no chance that you can
have that kind of problem, but there are
chance you have a problem somewhere
somehow.
You know, the biggest unknown is, is
geopolitics, you know, And it's not like
you have to be dangerous.
You carefully you talk about is not like
that's going to determine what the
economy does in 2026.
But it is a moving tectonic plate, you
know, alliances, You know, obviously,
this terrible war in Ukraine, which we
need to do as much as we can help
Ukraine, but aided and abetted by in
Russia and Russia, somewhat by China,
those folks have told you what they want
to do.
They want to dismantle their system set
up, they think, by America, set up by
the Western world after World War Two.
It's been quite successful.
Yeah, there are a lot of forces at play
and, you know, and people are going to
choose, you know, how they want to play
this, play this for now.
So yeah, that would be my greatest
concern.
And that's about the future of the free,
democratic world.
That's not just about America.
Are you worried about the overregulation
that some people in the banking world
think that is occurring now, or do you
think the regulations are okay now?
The problem with regulations, when you
talk to some people, it's always act
like it's more or less well, in the law
you do have regulation.
I think you can create more liquidity in
the system, you know, more capital use,
more linear capability, reduce rules and
regulations which cause those complaints
about banking and complaints.
But I think we can make the system
better work better, cheaper work for
more Americans and safer.
What bothers me the most is when we talk
about regulation, no one ever steps back
and say, What are we trying to
accomplish or Why do we want to
accomplish much better this or that?
Because no matter what you do, the pros
and cons banks are very strong today,
But take the system as a whole.
We've gone from 8000 public companies to
4000 public companies.
Is that what we wanted?
Because that's what we did.
We did it with no forethought without
even thinking about it.
But it was, you know, years of rules and
regulations.
That made it costly and litigious in
hard.
And, you know, we let institutions like
ISIS in glass Lewis you know, vote 30%
of the shares in America.
You know and and so yeah I'm quite
concerned about that.
We get regulations right.
We all want a safe financial system.
A safe food is safe.
But it doesn't mean you have to have
endless regulations.
Regulations should be reviewed and
improved all the time as opposed to what
we do today.
I put that in a lot of policy.
We just add things on top of things.
And if you look at policy in America,
more affordable housing, it's all about
policy.
You know, zoning policies, permitting
policies, housing policies, you know,
it's all about policy.
He's got not a damn thing to do.
The people don't want to build homes or
move into homes.
You know, and I can say to you about a
mortgage business, we made it more
expensive because of rules and
regulations, education, You know, we
don't measure the outcomes of high
schools in community colleges and
colleges, how many jobs they get, at
what income levels, and we could do it.
So we look at work skills.
We're going to need 2000 welders.
We need welding schools.
So if government can have policies of
policy that age in a better sense and
has the guardrails to create the right
behaviors, you know, not endless
policies that like slow things down,
which is what we have, you know, we're
go we're slowly going the way Europe,
you know, Europe, you may not know this
has gone from 90% per person GDP of
America to 65%.
That's what they've done.
It was all policy.
A lot of the policy done in the name of
good.
And that's what we do all the time.
We're endless, you know, rules and
regulations that create these things.
I also think you all should learn to
call it not red tape, but blue tape.
Okay.
The Democrats love that crap and then
they want to make it litigious.
You know that every flaw ever that ever
happens is on purpose by by bad people.
So policy, we need good policy.
And we're going to be fighting much more
for good policy this year.
Jp morgan Now, are you worried about the
size of the U.S.
debt?
We have $38 trillion of debt.
We're adding 2 trillion every year.
Do you see any way that's going to be
solved?
And do you worry that this is going to
impact the value of the dollar at some
point?
So if you look at the economy today,
there's a lot of good short term things
like think of this year.
You know, the one big beautiful build is
a lot of stimulus.
The Fed is buying bonds again.
That's you know about they don't call it
QE.
I would, but it lifts up asset prices
and stabilizes markets.
Deregulation is is real and it's going
to also drive animal spirits.
A lot of investment come into the
states.
And I that's all good and that's
probably going to drive stuff.
There are I call this geopolitics and
the deficit.
I call I call my tectonic plates.
They're difficult.
They're moving.
They may crash.
We don't know and we don't know when.
So it isn't a 2026 issue, but our
deficit is almost $2 trillion this year.
Total debt is 30 trillion.
That'll be next year, 32 and 34 and 37
and 40.
It is not sustainable.
It will not work eventually.
I just don't know when that is.
The best anecdote is growth.
I mean, if you just model anything,
growth will make up for it.
And that and growth.
I always tell people good policy is
free.
Like we already spent $800 billion in
K-12.
You know, stopping people from building
stuff is free.
It'll create jobs or create
productivity.
And so we have time to get the policy
right to grow the economy.
And then we have to start making some
other choices to was a president United
States said, I'd like you to be
secretary of the Treasury or chairman of
the Federal Reserve Board.
What would you say to that?
You are chairman of the Fed.
I'd be absolutely, positively no change,
no way, no how for any reason.
Okay.
Secretary Treasury, I would consider if
a president calls you up and asks you to
do something, you know, you should
consider it.
So I would take the call and consider it
and think about why and what they want,
etc..
But what they want and how they want to
operate would be important to me.
I like my job.
I've been my own boss for pretty much 25
years and I like it that way.
So recently there's been some comment by
you about the independence of the
Federal Reserve Board.
What more might you want to say about
your view about the importance of the
independence of the Federal Reserve
Board?
You know, too much ink is building
certain things.
Everyone I know, including the
president, United States, says we need
an independent Fed board.
The question is only about when certain
things take place and think of lawsuits
and stuff like that.
Does it chip away at that independence
of some spectrum?
So you can say a little bit, you can say
a lot, but you don't want to chip away
too much because if you chip away too
much, in my view, it in my opinion, it
will drive rates higher, not lower.
That's all.
That's not a job you would take.
If the United States said to you, I'd
like you to be a chairman, you're be
very independent.
You wouldn't.
I would So much more prefer this job
than that job.
That's a hard job.
But I don't want to do that job.
You went to Harvard Business School,
graduated with Baker scholar, top 5% of
your class.
You could have gone to Goldman Sachs,
Morgan Stanley, all your famous firms.
You chose to go work for a person who
was a friend of your father's name is
Sandy.
While you did that.
And then when Sandy left, you stayed
with him.
And then ultimately you guys went to
Citicorp and then he fired you.
Did you ever think then that you'd be
coming back and running the most
important bank in the world at the time
you got fired there, or what were you
thinking at that time?
And I said, You should come into private
equity.
I went to see you and I said, Why don't
you come to private equity?
And you, you didn't seem that
interested.
But the biggest money offer I ever got
in my life was from this guy over here.
It was never about money for me.
And I knew after I got fired that they
were going to screw up Citi because I
knew how stupid some of the things they
were doing was.
But no, and I didn't I didn't think that
way.
I just, you know, I took time.
I thought about all of these various
alternatives.
I spoke to a lot of people, you know,
and then I went to Bank one.
I love the Home Depot guys.
They were talking to me and but I had to
confess to them when I walked in.
I'd never been in Home Depot until my
friend made me go that weekend before I
had dinner with Arthur Blank, Bernie
Marcus and Ken Langone.
And I just loved their culture.
But I'd never been in a merchant
business.
And your bank was there.
I thought I was going be tough.
I put my money into to move my money to
Chicago.
I love Chicago.
All I thought about is just do the best
you can.
I mean, I don't like when senior people
complain.
I always had to know why is I suck it up
and do the job?
That's all it was.
And that's I just go about to work, you
know, and you're division by division,
person by person, department, joy by
tech, by tech, you know, try to build
something great.
I had my eye in JPMorgan Chase and, you
know, a couple of years I thought it
would never happen because we were so
small and not doing well.
But, you know, four years later, we had,
you know, done a good job of Bank one.
The values were close enough.
Bill Harris and I know each other.
We merge the two companies.
Then I had a dream that if we did it
right, we could make this a great
company.
Then I really did like that was What do
you think is the most important thing
you did that put Jp morgan ahead of
every other bank in the world?
You worked harder, you hired better
people around you.
What were the things that you think
their most important thing that made Jp
morgan what it is today, which I want?
A lot of people do things better.
So to say we're the best, everything is
not right.
And I think that's one of the reasons
why we do better a little bit, which is,
you know, I'm relentless.
Go through system by system, by system
by system, get out in the road, you
know, visit other companies.
They all do things better.
And you learn, learn, learn, learn,
learn and be run knows about doing it.
Big companies slow down, they become
complacent, become bureaucratic, all
that stuff arrogant, you know, is the
petri dish of politics.
You know, Jeff Bezos says, you know,
that kind of stuff leads to status and
death.
And if you don't believe me, I know you
look at all the companies you failed
huge, wonderful companies.
That's what management is.
It's relentless attention to detail,
getting strategy right, invest in your
capital, not be beholden people.
But the most important is the people at
their company can contribute the best of
their ability.
They know that you, the boss, don't know
everything and they know you just want
to do the right thing for the company.
Decline of the community.
And that's the only goal.
There's no other goal.
We don't pander to Wall Street about,
you know, quarterly earnings or stuff
like that.
I never spent any time in that in my
life.
I just try to do the right thing for the
right reason and do it quickly.
Your market capitalization is up about I
guess it's about the 700% and your stock
price up about 500% or something like
that, like 1,000%.
But go ahead.
How much we pay back?
We went back a long time and paid a lot
of dividends and all that.
So, yeah, so it's pretty good time.
So people are very happy.
And so the question you get asked every
day five times a day is how much longer
do you want to do this?
And the answer is five more years.
Yeah, at least about five more years.
I love what I do.
It's up to the board how long I do it.
I was honored to have the energy and the
the eye and the fire in the gut.
Yeah, I want to do it.
You recently built a new building in New
York.
Why did you decide to build your
headquarters in New York?
You tore down the building you had built
The new building, took a couple of years
and cost maybe $3 billion or something
like that.
And it's now open.
Are you happy you made that decision?
And are you going to build a similar
building in London now?
Yeah, we are.
So if you look at we have we spend $40
billion a year on people, which is
important, $4 billion a year on real
estate.
We want to have great, great real
The old building wasn't fit for purpose,
was too small, couldn't handle our
trading floors.
I looked everywhere.
I looked downtown, I looked Hudson
Yards.
I looked at Occupy and Vanderbilt.
But we could tell that building down, we
could buy air rights.
You know, I thought it was the best
location and the best city.
Many people in the business world,
they're out socializing all kinds of
other organization.
You don't do anything.
You just run your bank and you spend
time with your family.
Isn't that boring?
No, I love my family.
I love all of them.
I got seven grandkids and one more come
in.
We take our family vacation together.
That's.
The most important thing.
And the second most important is my
country that I do not spend time on.
You know, with my own time, my own
effort, my company obviously gets
involved.
I love business.
I think if I you know, I don't do a lot
of black ties.
I don't play golf, I don't do red
carpets.
I do a little bit, you know, But I love
what I do.
I mean, it's not like I don't feel like
I have any regrets at all about doing
that.
And I feel, you know, Jp morgan Chase
does well.
I could help our employees.
I help my clients, I help my community
to help my country.
I help the world if I do a good job.
You know, I always tell people, you
know, if we don't keep Jamie healthy and
vibrant, I cannot do those things.
That's when the other side that lay
people off, you're miserable, Your life
is terrible.
And I'm so.
I fight hard to make sure we're healthy
and vibrant.
Almost all of the bad policies we have
hurts lower paid people more than anyone
in this room.
So in some ways we could ignore it
because it's not really affecting us.
And that's what we did.
That was us.
That was all policy.
Warren Buffett more or less invented the
idea of writing a letter to shareholders
that everybody reads.
You have done the same.
And now Warren Buffett is probably not
going to write as Larry more.
Yours is widely read.
How much time do you put into writing
that letter?
And do you get nervous that so many
people are going to pay attention?
Every single word.
You have to get it exactly right.
Yeah, I do all that you are.
You bring his letters my whole life.
And I fact, I got his letters from 1956
when it was a partnership in private.
And and he said you should speak to your
Sheryl like your smart sister or mother
or something like that.
Explain to them what you're doing and
why you're doing it.
So I do that.
I make a list of questions.
I get the questions.
I do it myself.
I ask shareholders, I get you know, my
management team are like, what is the
most important stuff for JPMorgan?
And and I can't make that list.
I start right.
I spend a lot of time on it very often.
I used to answer the question, I don't
know the answer, and I actually do the
work.
So now I do a lot of research when I'm
writing the letter to answer the
question, What are we going to do?
Is what we did the right thing?
Should we do more of it?
How are you going to use it?
You know, I or, you know, open banking
or whatever, the question is debating
what is the real issue.
Then I try to explain it in terms to our
people, and then I start doing public
policy because no bank is actually
stronger, much stronger than the country
that lives in America.
From 2000 to 2020, grew 2% a year, had
to grow 3% a year, which I think was
eminently achievable.
Our GDP per person would be $20,000 more
year today per person, which would
afford a lot of safety nets, a lot of
infrastructure, had a lot of taxes, and
we didn't do it.
And it's around, you know, basic things.
Do I start to do more of that?
What are the things that we could do?
They can, you know, foster growth,
secure the country, make it healthier,
place lift up all of our citizens,
almost all of the bad policies we have.
The thing, though, that inner city
schools don't work, immigration policy,
you know, some of the stuff we do in
immigration permitting policies,
schools, almost all of that hurts low
paid people more than anyone in this
room.
So in some ways we could ignore it
because it's not really affecting us
directly.
Your kids don't go to those schools.
You know, I was worried about that.
You know, they have the lower income
folks have worse health care, worse job
prospects is become intergenerational.
Their schools don't work.
They have more crime.
And that's what we did.
That was just that was all policy.
And, you know, and then people stayed
behind ideology or morality, you know,
on both sides, you know, thinking that
they did stuff to fix it and they
didn't, you know.
And so I you know, I have frustration
around that.
Obviously, I feel the same way about the
security, resiliency, things, things
like permitting.
I make a list of what are the more how
are we do mortgage mortgages, affordable
housing.
So we may start a new one called the
American Dream.
We do a lot to do mortgages, affordable
housing, health care, skills, jobs.
You know, I would double the program
target or something like that.
There are a lot of things we could do
that would go to 3% and help all of our
citizens and secure the nation.
And we better do it pretty quick because
on the security side, we don't have
forever.
Of all the things you do is the most
enjoyable.
Getting to meet with members of Congress
when you come down here.
Is that an uplifting experience?
When you come down and meet with
members, how do you like that?
So you should know, I do it all the
time.
You know, it's part of my job.
I like years ago I said, you know,
government deserves another line of
business.
It is.
We take it seriously.
And to make an important point here in
the chamber, does this which you I think
they do a great job, but there are a lot
of people in the Congress, House and
Senate, who want to do the right job and
they need help to do the right job.
I'm not insulting their intelligence.
They're quite bright.
But, you know, they need the research,
the facts, the analysis to figure out
what to do when these complex issues
come up.
So I think we all need to do it.
And the only thing I would urge you all
to do when you do it don't always make
it parochial about your own
self-interest.
It should also be about which, in the
interest the United States of America,
you're all going to find anyway.
What happens from, you know, unions and
government and businesses where the
self-interest is so high.
It actually is part of why we have 2%
growth.
And I think we should all like open our
eyes a little bit, make sure we do the
right things.
You know, it's okay to fight for.
It's for you, you know, for your own
interests.
But but there's too much of that going
on.
I mean, you can't be working all the
time.
Do you have any hobbies, do anything
other than three about worry about the
Jp morgan, my daughters, who I also love
deeply and I've wonderful son in law,
was once said to be Dad, you need more
hobbies.
And I was like, What are you talking
about?
We take all our family vacations
together, you know, around the world.
We enjoy it.
I love history of wine and the music of
reading.
I love arts, I love we watch movies
together.
That's what I like.
I'm not looking to do other stuff and we
hike together.
So that's what I like.
Those are my sports.
We all do a gym together.
We have lunches and dinners together,
family dinners, like almost every
Saturday or Sunday night.
That's what I like and that's what I'm
going to do until I'm no longer here.
And.
Do you?
Have you ever had your credit card
denied?
I mean, you have a lot of
anybody ever denied Jamie Dimon.
Yes.
My own credit cards denied me several
times.
So what do you what do you tell them who
you are?
Well,
it doesn't work to tell them who you
are.
They don't know who I am.
How did your parents live to see your
success?
And what did they say to.
They say we always knew you were going
to be the CEO of Jp morgan.
It was going to do well.
What did they say?
My mom had a little of that.
You'll be a general one day or something
like that.
But they both died in 2016, literally
together in the same bed, same within 12
hours of each other.
So they got to see, you know, a lot of
it.
And we're quite proud.
You know, my you know, my grandparents
were all Greek immigrants who didn't
finish high school.
If I'm part of that story and they
instilled in all of us, you know, values
and the values have a purpose, work
hard, make the world a better place,
treat everyone, treat everyone properly
and equally.
What would you like people to know the
most about Jp morgan?
If they walk away from here today.
What would you like people to take back
in their head about Jp morgan, about
what it is, what it's done, or what it
stands for?
That we will stand by.
Good clients.
The thicker thin that we always try to
be better, that we are strong.
But their strength is for you.
That we want their community better.
We want your company to be better.
We want the country to be better.
We'll do our part in making this a
better world.
And we do it with aforethought and with
every sinew of our body to try to do the
best we can.
And if you and we God knows we make
mistakes, we will say we made a mistake,
we're sorry and we'll fix it.
That's what we'll do.
Do.